hello everyone welcome to another week
of holotalk this is Holo talk for the
week of
no it's not March anymore it's April
April 5th even though we're going up on
the 7th uh the reason why we're coming
up on the seventh is because we had Dr
Jay Ong he was away on vacation we
didn't up to Tuesday of last week so he
wanted to leave him up until Monday
night of this week to give him a fair
shake so uh we're putting this show up
on Tuesday but if you listen to last
week's show you already know that and
that's why you're tuned in today to hear
the new show
uh announcements lasers and Holograms
which is a traveling exhibit of the
Pacific Science Center is going to be
coming to the Discovery Center of
Science and Technology of Lehigh
University it's going to be here through
the summer and that's in Bethlehem
Pennsylvania which is just next to
Allentown which is just North West of
Philadelphia and it's a traveling
exhibit with a laser holography
um
touring exhibit a lot of interactive
things for parents and children to do
and they
pretty nice exhibit of holograms some
very large format Holograms of a couple
by uh Dr John Perry who's going to be a
guest on May 10th on this show
so if you get a chance if you live in
the New York Philly Baltimore Washington
D.C Carter it's a quick drive for you in
fact it's a Non-Stop drive for you from
anywhere in Baltimore Washington fill
your
um New York City you can come in
Non-Stop the first red light that you
will get that you'll have to stop is
just two blocks from the Discovery
Center so it's a quick drive our guests
I'd like to go down the list of guests
that we have
every so often I'll go down the entire
list this list is going to take us right
into fall of 98 so coming up on April
12th we have Steve province of Blue
Ridge holographics
and I just sent Steve an email tonight
letting him know that he's on for this
week so as soon as I hear back from him
we'll do the interview and get that up
as soon as possible and hopefully we'll
have it up for you uh Sunday night as
planned with our regular broadcast
April 26th is L Michael Robertson he's
with laser FX International that's an
organization that does all the laser
light shows around the world so he's
going to give us a perspective on how
laser light shows are put together and
you might want to tune in in case you
were thinking of actually doing a few
laser light shows of your own I hear
that's taken off it's getting pretty big
where people are getting some laser
light show equipment going around and
doing nightclubs and school dances and
some of the other things that are going
on so you want to tune in for all
Michael Roberts
Dr John Perry from holographics North
and they manufacture very large format
white light transmission Holograms up
there the con you see at the conventions
and at the large museums and like I
mentioned a little earlier
one of the Dr Perry's Holograms is
included in the laser and hologram
exhibit that's going to be coming to the
Discovery Center
May 24th Jason sapan of holographic
studios in New York City this the studio
that also is probably one of the nice
nicest galleries that we have in the
Northeast part of the country you can go
in and actually tour the gallery itself
I see a lot of holograms on displays and
he's going to probably fill us in on
a couple of the production runs that
he's doing in his Studios as well
because he has all of his holographic
tables and Laboratories right there at
the location as well June 7th is Peter
Shire from ad2000 which is a marketing
company for holography and I think with
an email that he had sent me earlier
that he wants to discuss holography with
short runs these are people who want to
have Holograms done but they don't
necessarily need 10 million of them from
for a magazine covers so I think he's
going to cover uh focus on short run
holography
Steven Quest is from Quest laser light
shows and once again that's going to be
on June 21st and he had another laser
light show uh show that we're going to
have here on Hollow talk so if you're
interested in laser light shows tune in
for Steven Quest
July 12th George caligaris and I think
I'm pronouncing that name right I'm not
quite sure George is a teacher he's been
teaching holography for many many years
he has a website up for amateur
holography and holography and education
which is a very popular site and he's
going to be covering just that on Joe
Nina the week of July 12th holography
and education and probably more or less
for the amateur and hobbyist holographer
July 26th is Arlene jurich and she also
is involved with the holography and
education she's been teaching holography
for many many years I've known or Arlene
going way back and he teaches some very
unique things using Holograms as models
for the brain and how the brain
functions and especially in learning age
of children so that's would have been
interesting show you want to tune in for
August 2nd Sharon McCormick and Sharon
has done some very famous Holograms that
you may have seen around like Sports
Illustrated cover that has
Michael Jordan and
also she did I believe a CD cover
for print among other things and in any
case we'll also have a link to her
holography site we can go on and see all
the work that she's done August 16th
which is getting close to closing out
the southern summer we have Stephen
Michael and Stephen has a wonderful
holography site for amateur holography
and we're going to have him on talking
about amateur and hobbyist holography
and talk about his website and the
different things and projects he's been
working on in amateur and hobbyist
holography so that's our lineup running
from April 12th which is coming up this
week to August 16th of this year which
is going to take us into fall and that's
all I have on the sheet because there's
still probably another show or two in
August but that's only between the sheet
and I don't see another sheet with it
anyway that should be enough for
everybody
okay let's move on we'll do some
questions this week
we got a shortage of questions for a
while it was a dry spell didn't get any
calls or any emails it was depressing
and then all of a sudden
got like four or five of them here just
uh from in the last week
you've got me
okay this question's coming from Michael
and Michael asked could you please tell
me if anybody has used a hologram of the
Magazine advertisement would this be
very expensive Plus
you have a hologram of a cat and then if
you hold it one way you see a dog
yeah I can tell you about the magazine
coverage there's quite a few well you
said magazine advertisements but there's
been mostly on covers I would say um
just to grab people's attention
um Justified the cost of making a
hologram and and the production run of
putting one on
a printed piece it's a lot better to put
it on the cover because you get the
opportunity to grab someone's attention
when that Magazine's on the stand I've
seen them used I think car and driver
had a Ford Taurus on it Sports
Illustrated had Michael Jordan uh let's
see what else can I think of of course
we had the National Geographic covers
and as far as advertisements I've seen
them in quite a few advertisements we've
got the absolute vodka which was a full
page ad that was just a hologram
excuse me the McDonald's
restaurant chain took the back cover of
one of the
National Geographic covers in fact the
entire cover was nothing but a hologram
so it's it's used is it very expensive
um
I get the impression from a lot of
people that are involved with the
printing industry that it is very
expensive to them when you compare that
to other traditional uh premium type of
printing that you can do to grab
people's attention they do consider it
expensive the actual prices I don't have
at this point I imagine
back when the National Geographic covers
were at and you know a lot of these
things were quite a few years ago it was
didn't have as much competition in the
marketplace and the price was high but I
bet if you went shopping around you
could probably find something that was
in the price range that you were looking
for go to the link page at the web scene
and there's a whole page of links and
I'm sure there's at least
a half dozen companies on there that you
could go to their website and find out
exactly what they do for a holographic
printing uh if you have a whole grain of
a cat man if you hold it one way you see
a dog yeah they're called multiple
Channel Holograms or some Holograms have
160 200 300 individual exposures uh when
you get into the stereograms but a lot
of holograms are multiple Channel
Holograms people find them fascinating
when they're in the store and they can
look it at one side and see one thing
look at it another way to see another
thing a couple of them that come to mind
are the Star Trek Holograms
I think one's a borg I'm not familiar
too familiar with the Star Trek
characters but I think ones are more
gonna changes into different things as
you move and there's another one which
is a computer mouse
we see a little real Mouse on top of a
computer mouse that you use with your
hand and as you move past the Hologram
you see you know different images and it
does different things so yeah you can do
that and they're called multiple Channel
Holograms and the public always wants to
see something happen with a hologram and
that's that's the way to do it you know
put multiple Channel Holograms out there
and if if someone walks into a shop and
they just see a hologram and it doesn't
do anything they're always asking what's
this hologram supposed to do it doesn't
do anything well some Holograms don't do
anything they're just Holograms you know
look at them and enjoy it just for what
it is
uh second question
uh this is coming from RW and in the
last name I won't say the last name so
we'll just say it's from RW is it
possible to make or design holographic
images by computer yes it is
um we're we're using a computer to do uh
Holograms of the Titanic and what we're
doing is we have the archival film
footage from the Titanic expedition
Expeditions excuse me from uh Bob
Ballard and Dr Ballard I've been working
with the Jason project for a couple
years now and Dr Ballard's involved with
that project and I've got some of the
Expedition footage from the Titanic and
what we're doing is uh
you have to it has to meet certain
criteria in order to make it a good
hologram the camera has to be moving
horizontally as it's passing the object
and then you can take individual frames
and then
synthesize them into a holographic
stereogram frame by frame
so that's one way of using a computer
now can you make a hologram directly
from computer computer information yes
you can if you have a 3D design program
you can design an object and take a
frame so many degrees of rotation and
send that to a frame printer and then
rotate it a few more degrees and send
that to another frame printer where it
comes out on film and you can use that
film frame by frame to do the same thing
and I believe I I've read I I don't know
how popular this is or how often this
occurs but I I believe that computers
can actually write holographic
information itself and create a hologram
specifically from the data data self
rather than the image and then it goes
to a holographic printer that exposes
the film or the plate that almost pixel
by pixel and it's an incredibly long
process to do that
I'm trying to think of a third way I had
it right in the back of my head and I'm
losing it here hold on
well I put it on pause to try and think
of this other way and that quick it's
gone I guess so nobody's starting to set
in but anyway that should give you a
couple examples of computer Holograms
computer holography
okay hello I'm David I won't say the
last name oh I was at your Workshop okay
I have one of my workshop participants
so I have two questions about lasers and
Holograms the first one is how a laser
is made
second one is how our whole grants made
well geez I'll tell you what David I
mean
uh we did cover this in the workshop but
maybe you just want me to
answer the question on the air I
understand I understand uh lasers are
made
well there's a lot of different lasers
and it would take a long time to go
through all the different types of
lasers that there are to that it's a
long question and a long answer to a
short question to go into that
the most popular lasers I'll tell you
this are helium neon lasers used for
holography most of your amateur and
obvious holographers are using helium
neon lasers are very inexpensive they
have a long life about twenty thousand
dollars plus
and um they're basically a glass tube
that is uh
about the size of a drinking straw the
actual uh place where the glazing action
takes place and that glass tube is
filled with the mixtures of the gases
helium and neon it's the same helium
that you find in helium birthday
balloons the same neon you find in the
neon Pizza signs when you go out at
night to pick up a pizza and just like a
pizza sign and when you apply power to
that tube that tube lights up just like
the pizza sign does now even though most
of the lights escaping through the sides
of the tube we do have mirrors that are
placed on the ends of the tube and the
light begins to reflect back and forth
between the two years one of the mirrors
is partially reflective which means when
the light is being reflected back and
forth between those two mirrors this
specific mirror allows a certain amount
of the light to come through a certain
percentage and that comes through as a
laser beam
uh how are Holograms made where
Holograms are made using the laser
there are certain properties of laser
light that we need in order to make a
hologram the light needs to be
monochromatic which means it's one color
and one color only added time
and the light source also has to be
coherent which means all of the waves
that are traveling out of that laser are
in step with one another and what I like
the term wave train
Senator it's these properties of the
laser itself and the laser light
specifically that allow us to make the
Hologram the Holograms are made in
usually a holographic Labs either
professional Laboratories or amateur
Studios you find some people's basements
and even out in garages
there's a holographic table that's
usually used in this holographic table
is used to dampen vibrations coming up
from the floor it needs to be a very
stiff table so that you don't get a lot
of flex and that laser beam travels
around the table
for a simple hologram you just need one
bean with the object placed behind the
plate and spread that laser beam out and
cover it with light
I have more complex Holograms you take
that laser beam and break it up into a
bunch of different beams using a beam
splitter extend it on table you may have
one two three or more object beams
illuminating your object and one beam
which is specifically used to illuminate
the holographic plate or film which is
called the reference beam
it doesn't have to be a very complex
process it can be very simple and you
don't necessarily have to have a large
holographic table I've made holograms on
top of table tops just using a
few simple items in order to make the
Hologram itself
so David I hope that answers your
question thank you very much for sending
it in I hope you enjoyed the workshop
here we have another another question
that was sent in from email
this is from Farah
I am doing a report for school
concerning Holograms my problem is that
I can't find any good information
regarding the Optics involved with
holography please send me any
information you can answer it on your
Hollow talk show
uh pharaoh
I
should go to the
link and try and find one of the links
then just go down the page and read the
descriptions and find if uh see if you
can find a site that deals a little bit
more with holography and the Optics I
know there has to be something out there
on the web that will give you some
information on the Optics but like I
answered with David's question we do not
need to have a very complex Optical
system in order to do Holograms
to do a hologram
the least amount of Optics that you
would need would just be one lens which
would take that laser beam and spread it
out and give it enough area to cover the
holographic plate with the object behind
it and that
single beam reflection hologram that you
can view with white light
there are other pieces of optical
equipment that you can add to your
system for more complex setups things
such as collimating mirrors which takes
the diverging wave front of that
expanding laser light and puts it into a
parallel beam
also there are spatial filters which the
light can go through it goes through an
objective lens which focuses it down to
a very small point
and at that point
there is a pinhole which is usually 10
25 microns in diameter it's very tiny
and we pass that laser light right at
that focal point through the pinhole
in the spatial filter that cleans up the
profile of the beam anyone who's done
amateur holography knows that a lot of
times when you take a beam and you send
it through a lens and you show that
expanded
white card you'll notice that it's uh
it's not it's pretty crappy looking
sometimes if you're just using a lens
what a spatial filter does
is it cleans that profile it's actually
a beautiful spread light
a spread beam of laser light that
focuses uh not focuses but shows up on
the white card and it really improves
the overall quality of the Holograms
immensely when you use a spatial filter
but it's not necessary to do that
so there are questions for the week
I don't think we have any more thank you
very much for sending the questions in
if you have any more questions please
send them in we try to get the questions
in on the odd weeks every other week we
have a guest and every other week beside
that we have the odd week which we do
different things and a lot of times
those things are answering questions so
not to make this show run on and on and
on so what I'm going to say is thank you
very much for tuning in remember our
guest next week is Steve Province from
Blue Ridge holographics and if
everything goes as planned that show
will go up in August August jeez April
12th which is Sunday night so you want
to tune in and see if that shows up if
it's not up I'll have a message to let
you know when to expect that show to be
up
tuning in the whole talk this is Frankie
Freitas take care and see you next week